奇遇电影字幕组
QY-182
圣巴巴拉 1979年
那是我丈夫的福特银河
That was my husband's Ford Galaxy.
我们从医院接杰米回家
We drove Jamie home...
开的就是那辆车
from the hospital in that car.
我妈妈生我的时候四十岁了
My mom was 40 when she had me.
每个人都对她说 她年纪太大 不适合做母亲了
Everyone told her the she was too old to be a mother.
我把手伸进那个小窗子 他握住了我的手指
I put my hand through the little window and he squeezed my finger.
然后我告诉他们 生命无比伟大
And I tell 'em, life was very big.
又充满未知
And unknown.
她告诉我世界上有动物
And she told me that there were animals.
天空 城市
And sky and cities.
音乐
Music.
电影
Movies.
他会坠入爱河
He'd fall in love.
会有自己的孩子 会有自己的热爱
Have his own children. Have passions.
会找到人生的真谛
Have meaning.
也有妈妈爸爸
Have his mom and dad.
然后 他们离婚了
And they got divorced...
我爸爸搬回了东部 把这辆车留给了我们
My father moved back east and left the car with us.
他会在我生日和圣诞节的时候打电话来
He calls on birthdays and Christmas.
我上一次感到亲近他
Last time I felt close to him,
是1974年我生日时
was on my birthday in 1974.
他给我买了一副镜面太阳镜
He bought me mirrored sun glasses.
我看到总统摔下楼梯
I saw the President fall downstairs.
我还吐在了地毯上
And I threw up on the carpet.
从那以后 我们俩相依为命
Since then it's just been us.
因为你要搭那班飞机
Because you're getting on that plane.
电影《卡萨布兰卡》
我不明白 那你呢
I don't understand. What about you?
我会留在这看住他 直到飞机飞走
I'm staying here with him till the plane gets safely away.
不 理查德 不 这是怎么回事 昨晚我们说过...
No Richard no, what has happened? Last night we said...
昨晚我们说了很多
Last night we said a great many things.
对了 队长
Listen, Captain.
今晚我家有个聚会 因为今天是我生日
I am having a party tonight, it's my birthday actually.
我希望你们能来 我好表达一下感谢
And I would like you to drop by, So I can feed you.
你不用这么客气的 菲尔茨女士
NIt's not necessary, Ms. Fields.
叫我多萝西娅就行 不 一定要来
No, Dorothea, no... I insist.
拜托了
Please.
那车其实挺漂亮的
It was a beautiful car.
妈妈 车里老有一股汽油味 还常常过热
Mom, It smelled like gas and overheated all the time.
就是辆旧车
It was just old.
什么
What?
好吧 也不是一直那么旧 就是突然成那样了
Well, it wasn’t always old. Just got that way all of a sudden.
你知道吗
You know?
消防员来的时候
When the firemen come...
人们一般不会邀请他们一起吃晚餐的
people don't usually invite them for dinner.
是吗 为什么不呢
Yeah, why not?
翻译        阿囤小兄弟   FantaJoe
StillWhale     butterfliesaway
校对     一个Delpy　/　特效&压制     33-eR
二十世纪女人
Talking Heads- Don't Worry About the Government?
怎么就是没法放下过去
Why can't I just move on...
快乐地生活
be happy with my life, and...
把责任都推到他身上呢
bring blame on him.
那只会让我觉得自己不够好
That just makes me feel like I'm not good enough.
常常让我觉得跟我爸很像
It is inconstantly being compared to my dad.
嘿 抱歉
Hey, sorry.
杰米这会儿不在
Jamie's not here right now.
他们还没回来
They are not home.
别拍了
Don't.
我在给一天里和我产生交集的每一件事物拍照
I'm taking a picture of everything that happens to me in a day.
我不喜欢拍照
I don't like having my pictures taken.
也没跟你产生交集
I didn't happen to you.
有人吗
Hello.
- 嘿 嗨      - 嗨
- Hey, hi.        - Hi.
给我吧
Here.
你绝对不会相信
You aren't gonna believe...
- 出什么事了      - 怎么了
- what happened.        - What?
我们的车在停车场突然自燃了
Our car burst into flames in the parking lot.
呃…
Eh...
- 真的吗      - 你们没事吧
- Seriously?        - Are you okay?
嗯 我们没事
Yeah, we are okay.
怎么搞的
How did it happen?
我不知道 他们说可能是电路的问题
I don't know. They said it was probably just something electrical.
我们走过去 它就停在那
We walked down and it was just sitting there.
熊熊燃烧
On fire.
天呐
Oh Man!
- 对啊      - 我很遗憾
- Yes.        - I'm sorry.
所以
So...
情况怎么样
What happened...?
他们从来不会跟你透露一丁点信息
They never tell you anything.
一周后才会有结果
I will know anything for like a week.
还有我…我要晚点交房租了
And I'm.. I'm gonna be late on rent.
没关系 别操那个心
That's okay, don't worry about that.
谢谢
Thanks.
天呐
Oh God!
The Clash- (White Man) In Hammersmith Palais
如果那时你在车上该怎么办呢
What if you've been in the car?
那我就不会在这里了
I wouldn't be here.
你会想我吗
You would've missed me?
别开玩笑了
Don't joke.
别这么饥渴 这样我们才比较好相处
It's so much easier before you got all horny.
- 可是你不像是不…      - 做的人?
- But it's not like you don't...        - Do it?
朋友上完床就做不了朋友了
Friends can't have sex and still be friends.
我喜欢我们这种状态 好吗
I like us, like we are, okay?
好吧
Okay.
杰米 你能过来帮我布置一下吗
Jamie, Could you come help me set out please?
我妈能不能消停一会儿
Can my mom just chill out?
她在填补自己的寂寞
She is compensating for her loneliness.
多萝西娅 那些线脚非常漂亮
Dorothea, All that is really beautiful moulding.
的确
It is.
旁边我也想那样弄
I wanna continue that around the side.
那我们得重新搭配一下
Well, we are gonna have to rematch that.
那个…真的是木的吗
Now is that... Is that actually wood?
- 还是石膏的      - 下面一层是石膏
- Or is that plaster?        - The plaster is underneath it.
- 线脚在外面 还有木的      - 好的
- The moulding on the outside. There is wood.         - Okay.
这得要花点时间
It's gonna take a little bit of time.
- 可是…      - 没事 弄吧
- But...        - No, we got.
好了 就这样
Okay, no, it's good.
其实是1905年建的
Actually, it was built in 1905.
一直归同一个家族所有
And the same family had it forever,
但是战争期间他们倾家荡产了
but they lost all their money during the war.
后来这里还发生了火灾…
And then there was a fire and...
那时候要是有你在就好了
You should have been here for that.
总而言之
Anyway.
于是 这里变得一团糟 他们也放任不管
So... It was just a mess, they've let it fall apart.
六十年代一个波西米亚人继承了这房子
Then a bohemian inherited it in '60s...
于是许多精神自由的人搬了进来
and free spirits moved in.
- 后来他们的房子就被银行没收了      - 房子很漂亮
- And they lost it to the bank.        - It's beautiful.
我彻底爱上了它…
I completely fell in love with them...
我们与泥土相通
We are connected to the dirt,
因为我们来自于泥土 泥土由星辰而来
'cause we came from the dirt. The dirt is made of stars.
人类便是这样诞生的
and started out the same way that we are.
所以
So...
当你把手伸进泥土
When you put your hands into that...
感受大地母亲时...
Dirt and feel the Earth Mother.
威廉
William...
看来我还是需要一辆车
It look as though, I'm gonna be in need of a car.
你觉得你那有什么适合我的吗
Do you think that you have something for me out there?
便宜点的 那辆49豪华版可以吗
Cheap? Maybe that '49 Deluxe.
我想我们会有办法的
I think we can work something out,
也许我们可以拿房租来抵
Maybe we'll trade for rent or something.
- 谢谢你      - 不用谢
- Thank you.       - Sure
好了 那个问题解决了
Okay, got through that one.
好了 只是…等一会儿
Alright, just um.. give me a minute.
然后你再端出来
And then come out.
萝西娅・菲尔茨 生于1924年
我妈妈生于1924年
My mom was born in 1924.
她像我这么大时 人们
When she was my age, people...
驾驶着悲伤的车 驶向悲伤的房子
drove in sad cars to sad houses.
只有老式电话 没有钱或食物
With old phones, no money or food.
也没有电视
Or televisions.
但是人们活得真实
But people were real.
在她十六岁时
And when she was 16...
战争爆发了 她被迫辍学
the war broke out and she had to leave school.
她的梦想是成为一名美国空军的飞行员
Her dream was to be a pilot in the Air Force.
她真的上了飞行学校
She actually went to the flight school.
可她还没毕业 战争就结束了
But the war ended before she was done.
她成为大陆罐头公司绘图室的
She became the first woman to work...
第一位女性员工
In the Continental Can company drafting room.
然后 她遇到了我爸爸
Then she met my dad.
然后 我出生了
And then I came.
再然后 他们离婚了
And they got divorced.
但是她那个年代的人
But people from her time...
从不承认有什么地方出了差错
never admit anything went wrong.
您这是什么意思
What do you mean?
不好意思 他年纪太小了
I'm sorry, he is too young to have...
还不能以他个人的名义开账户
an account in his name only.
小家伙
Little guy.
不 他是一个人 不是半个人
No, he's a person, he's not half a person.
他也不是什么可爱的小鬼头
And he's not some cute little guy.
他有洞察力 自主权和隐私权
He has vision, autonomy and privacy.
他需要开一个银行账户
He needs a bank account.
您能给我们办理吗
Can you do that for us?
杰米 你不能总是旷课
Jamie, you can't just keep skipping...
还编借口
the school and making excuses.
等等 为什么不能
Wait a minute, why not?
他为什么不能旷课
Why you can't he just skip school?
如果他有正当的理由要旷课的话
If he has a legitimate need to be away.
好吧 那我需要您提供"正当的"真实请假条
Well, the I need a "legitimate" real note from you.
- 好的      - 和您真实的签名
- okay.        - With your real signature.
哇 你怎么把我的签名学得这么像的
Wow, how did you forged my signature so well?
真机智
That is ingenious!
但是你永远都不该伪造别人的签名
But you should never forge someone's signature...
背着他们做任何事
..Do anything behind someone's back.
请允许杰米今早不去上课
Please excuse Jamie from school this morning.
他在为桑地诺主义者做志愿工作
He was doing volunteer work for the Sandinistas.
请允许杰米今早不去上课
Please excuse Jamie from school this morning.
他发生了一起小型空难
He was involved in a small plane accident.
幸运的是 他没受伤
Fortunately, He was not hurt.
这绝对会是一个巨大的惊喜
Will be for a legendary surprise.
下层是红木
It's mahogany underneath.
她一直试图将一个男人带进我的生命
She's always trying to bring a man into my life.
这很可能是洪都拉斯红木
This is probably Honduran mahogany,
纹理真的很精美
Really fine grain.
这真的非常非常无聊
This is like, really really boring.
拜托 别乱说
Hey, Come on! Watch it.
他一直在说木头什么的
He's talking about like woods and stuffs.
他在帮我重修房子 好吗
He's helping me out restore the house, okay?
IBM公司
IBM
她每天早上她要记下手里股票的股价
She writes down her stocks every morning.
213.2美元
$213.20
通用
GE?
51.62美元
$51.62
她抽沙龙烟 因为比较健康
She smokes Salem, because they are healthier.
穿勃肯鞋 因为时下流行
Wears Birkenstocks because she is contemporary.
她看《兔子共和国》
She read "Watership Down"...
英国小说家理查德・亚当斯带有现实隐喻的奇幻小说
学习怎样雕刻木头兔子
And learned how to carve rabbits out of wood.
她从不跟男人长期交往
And she never dates a man for very long.
谢谢你 大力水手
Thank you, Popeye.
晚安 多萝西娅
Good night, Dorothea.
- 晚安       - 拜
- Goodnight.        - Bye.
那回头见了
So I'll see you later.
别再跟那个叫克里斯的家伙玩了 好吗
Just don't hang with that Chris guy anymore, okay?
他就是个傻逼
And he's kinda dumb.
没错
Exactly.
- 生日快乐       - 拜 朱莉
- Happy Birthday.        - Bye, Julie.
别笑了
Stop.
怎么了
What?
你以为你对发生的事情了如指掌
You think that you know everything that's going on.
不 我只是觉得
No, I just think that...
你知道吗 心碎是一种
You know having your heart broken, is a...
了解这个世界的绝佳方式
tremendous way to learn about the world.
行了
Okay.
你觉得你快乐吗
Do you think you're happy?
就像…
Like...
你在我这么大时想象自己将来一样快乐吗
As happy as you thought you'd be when you were at my age.
你是认真的吗
Seriously?
你不应该问别人那种问题
You don't ask people question like that.
你是我妈妈
You're my mom.
尤其是你妈妈
Especially your mom.
听着 成天想着自己是不是快乐
Look. Wondering if you are happy...
是通往抑郁的捷径
It's a great shortcut to just being depressed.
那个给我
Give me that.
The Raincoats- Fairytale in the Supermarket?
那是什么
What is that?
雨衣乐队
It's the "The Raincoats".
就不能唱得好听点吗
Can't things just be pretty?
"好听的音乐"是用来掩盖
"Pretty music" is used to hide...
社会的不公与腐败的
how unfair and corrupt society is.
好吧 所以
Okay so.
她们的音乐不怎么样
They are not very good.
The Raincoats是一支三人女子乐队
她们自己也知道 对吗
And they know that, right?
对
Yeah.
就好像她们感情充沛
It's like they have got all these feelings.
但她们没有技巧 也不想要技巧
And they don't have any skill, and they don't want skill
因为这样真的很有趣
because it's really interesting.
就是当你的热情超越了
What happens when your passion is bigger...
你用来表达热情的工具时
than the tools that you have...
会发生什么
to deal with it.
于是就产生了这种能量
It creates this energy.
这种 这种 这种摇滚力量
This..this.this rock.
这难道不好吗
Isn't it great?
我的儿子出生于1964年
My son was born in 1964.
伴随他成长的 是一场无意义的战争
He grew up with a meaningless war.
抗议
With protests.
尼克松
With Nixon.
豪车和洋房
With nice cars and nice houses.
计算机
Computers.
毒品
Drugs.
和百无聊赖
Boredom.
我对他的了解与日俱减
I know him less everyday.
他说那只是个游戏
He said it was just a game.
使劲呼吸 然后让另一个孩子勒住你的横膈膜
You breath real hard and another kid pulls on your diaphragm.
你就会晕倒
And you faint.
他说过几秒应该就会醒过来
He said you're supposed to come to a few seconds later.
- 我能试试吗      - 行
- Can I try?         - Yeah.
但是杰米过了差不多半个小时才醒过来
But it took Jamie almost half an hour to wake up.
快去找人帮忙
Go and get help.
能告诉我你的名字吗
Can you tell me your name?
杰米
Jamie.
杰米 你为什么要做
Jamie, why would you do something?
那么危险的事
So dangerous?
不知道
I don't know.
我是说 大家都做了
I mean, everyone was doing it.
那你就随大流吗
So you just went along with it?
看着挺好玩的
It looked like fun.
那太愚蠢了 你怎么会做那么蠢的事
That's just dumb, why would you do something so stupid?
就为随大流吗
Just following along?
你知不知道自己差点死了
Do you know you almost died..
好吗
Right?
- 你不用担心我      - 你做之前怎么不想想
- You don't need worry about me.        - Why didn't you think?
杰米 嘿
Jamie, Hey.
杰米
Jamie.
怎么回事 等等
What is going on? Wait.
怎么 你不准备跟我说话了吗
What? You are not gonna talk to me now?
不说话的那个人不是我
I'm not the one who doesn't talk.
什么
What?
得了吧
Come on!
你都快把我吓死了
You scared the hell out of me.
你为什么要那样伤害自己
Why did you hurt yourself like that?
那你为什么不要命地抽烟
Why do you smoke yourself to death?
嘿
Hey.
为什么你无所谓自己那么悲伤和孤独
Why are you fine being sad and alone?
我…
I...
我…你…
I... You...
你不能那样跟我说话 我们不…
You can't talk to me like that. We don't...
你不该跟我说那种话
You don't say that to me.
Rudy Vallée- As Time Goes By
我觉得历史对人很残酷
I think History has been tough on men.
我是说他们不能做自己 也看不清未来会怎样
I mean they can't be what they were. And they can't figure out what's next.
我们在讨论什么来着
What are we talking about?
人?
Men?
我觉得是历史和人
I think history and men.
我的意思是 现如今你们的英雄是谁
I mean, who are your heroes now a days?
一群享有特权的瘾君子吗
A bunch of privileged drug addicts?
我觉得你们也许能替我帮助杰米
I think maybe you guys can help me with Jamie.
我觉得
I think...
他需要有人帮助他弄清楚
He needs help in figuring out...
在这种糟糕的境遇中如何做自己
how to be himself in all this mess.
而我不能在场
And I can't be there.
我不能在他身边
I can't be there with him.
我得放手
I have to let go.
是因为晕倒那事吗
Is this because the fainting thing?
他没事
He's fine.
不 是因为所有事
No. It's because of everything.
我不明白你要我们做什么
I don't understand what are you asking?
你要怎样才能成为一个优秀的人
How do you be a good man?
这话放在当下是什么意思
What does that even mean now a days?
他只有我
He has only got me.
这还…
It's just...
你们想想 这是不够的
Think about it, it's not enough.
你是认真的
You are serious.
- 是      - 那威廉呢
- Yeah.        - What about William?
威廉是男人 那…
William's a guy. That's...
他可以跟他聊聊男人的事
He can talk to him about guy things.
你见过他们聊天吗
Have you ever seen them have a conversation?
他们毫无共同点 根本聊不来
They have nothing in common, they don't connect.
这不管用的
It's just not working.
我是说 我考虑过了
I mean, I thought about that.
他…
He...
他喜欢你
Well, He likes you.
还有你 他很喜欢你们俩
And you, He likes you a lot.
那…
That...
他是我朋友 我不想当他妈
That's my friend, I don't wanna be his mom.
没错 不 我才是他妈
Yeah, no, I'm his mom.
我是说 你不需要一个男人来帮他成长为男人吗
I mean, Don't you need a man to raise a man?
我不那样认为
No I don't think so.
我的意思是…
I mean...
我觉得能帮助他的是你们
I think you are what's gonna work for him.
我是说
I mean...
你比谁都了解他
You know him better than anyone.
这点你知道的
You know that.
而且
And...
你关心他 你可以照顾他
You care about him, You can watch out for him.
而你 跟他分享你的生活就可以了
And you... just share your life.
你那么有天赋 让他看看你感兴趣的东西
You're talented person, show him you're interested in.
那他就真是太幸运了
You know he will be lucky to have that.
帮我什么
Help me with what?
帮你度过你人生的这个阶段 这可不容易
Oh...Go through this part of your life, it's not easy.
对谁来说都不容易
It's not easy for anybody.
- 你要求她们帮我的?      - 对
- You asked them to help me?        - Yeah.
不 她们 她们明白
No, they.. They get it.
所以她们同意了
So they said yes?
对
Yeah.
操
Fuck!
嘿
Hey...
你就是觉得愧疚罢了 因为我爸爸不在
You just feel guilty cause it's just me and you.
我不知道我的感受
You don't know what I'm feeling.
那你告诉我啊
Just tell me.
小子
Kid.
你从不告诉我你准备做什么
You never tell me what you're gonna do.
你就直接去做了
You just do it.
Black Flag- I've Had It?
我弄到我后妈的车钥匙了
I got the keys to my step mom's car.
准备出发了
Wanna start at once
塔尼娅和米歇尔都会去
Tanya and Michelle, are both gonna be there.
嘿 你们要去洛杉矶?
Hey, you guys going to L.A.?
嗯
Yeah.
我去
I am.
我能去吗
Can I come?
各位 准备好了吗
Listen all. You ready?
- 好了      - 我们要…
- Yeah.        - We gonna...
你要去找乐子吗
Are you gonna get with some chicken?
是杰米
That was Jamie.
他在洛杉矶
He is in L.A.
他和几个朋友去看演出了
He and some friends went to a show.
- 哦      - 是的
- Oh.        - Yeah.
他让我转告你
He wanted to tell you.
好的
Okay.
你不担心吗
Aren't you worried?
他生我气了 这是他的应对方式
He's mad at me. And This is his way of dealing with it.
而且他有权利生气
And he has every right to be mad.
没错 但是如果这让他那么生气 可能就不是个好办法
Yeah, but if it makes him this mad, then maybe it wasn't a good idea.
Germs- Media Blitz?
可能
Maybe...
可能我做错了
Maybe I did the wrong thing.
我…
I...
- 我是说在教育孩子方面      - 嗯 我知道
- With the kid, I mean.        - Yeah I know.
我觉得杰米的能量非常…
I think that Jamie's energy is very...
不稳定
Unstable.
是啊 你说得对
Well, you're right.
接着他会有能量危机
Then there's an energy crisis, maybe that...
可能不知怎地就起作用了
Plays into it someway.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不怎么开玩笑 对吧
You don't have very..many funny lines do you?
好吧
Okay.
杰米...
Jamie...
杰米
Jamie.
Siouxsie/The Banshees- Love in a Void
嗨
Hey.
都还好吗
Everything okay?
挺好的
Yeah.
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
当然可以
Sure.
我对摄影有了一个新的想法
So I had this new idea for my photography.
我打算
I was gonna...
给我所有的物品拍照
take a picture of everything...
从而通过这些物品
That I own, so it will be self-portrait.
形成一个
Myself...
我的自画像
through the stuff that I have.
我可以给你看看吗
Can I show you?
这是...
So...
胸衣 避孕工具
Bra, birth control,
苏珊・桑塔格的《论摄影》
On Photography by Susan Sontag,
《论摄影》出版于1977年 被誉为"摄影界的《圣经》"
鞋子 内裤
Shoes, Underwear.
一张拍我母亲照片的照片
a picture of a picture of my mom.
我还要拍些其他的
I'm gonna do a bunch of them.
这有点...
It's a little bit...
有点忧伤
It's a little bit sad.
这些东西放在一块儿
You know, all these stuff together...
我不知道为什么会这样
I don't know why that is.
什么都没有 我的意思是
None, I mean...
你明白我的意思吗
You know what I mean?
真的很美 艾比
It's really beautiful, Abbie.
你想跟我上床吗
Do you wanna fool around with me?
真的吗
Really?
真的
Yeah.
好啊
我愿意
I do.
你知道的 我还在宫颈癌的康复期
You know...I'm recovering from cervical cancer.
我知道
I know.
你的头发很好闻
Your hair smells good.
我的洗发水是自制的
I make my own shampoo.
你当然用自制的了
Of course you do.
没关系的 吉夫斯 他回来了
It's OK Jeeves, he's back.
你可以放心了
You can relax now.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我们去了喜达屋 看了场演出
We went to the Starwood, saw a show.
就是在洛杉矶 我玩得很开心
You know, in LA I had a lot of fun.
你喝多了吗
Are you drunk?
不要
Don't.
怎么了
What's wrong?
蒂姆・德莱姆射我里面了
Tim Drammer came inside me.
我不想听这些屁话了
I don't wanna hear this shit.
我们溜进了一个娱乐中心的废旧泳池
We broke into that old pool at the rec center.
喝醉了
Got loaded.
到处疯
Fucked around.
最后我和蒂姆跑到他妈妈的福特翼虎车里
And me and Tim ended up in his mom's Maverick.
你刚刚射了?
Did you just cum?
射了
Yeah.
你说了你不会射里面的
You said you would pull out.
是啊
Yeah.
对不起
Sorry.
我们不是说好了吗
Thought we had a deal there.
操
Fuck!
你准备怎么办
What're you gonna do?
不会有事的
It'll be fine.
你妈让我帮忙抚养你
Your mom asked me to like, help raise you.
我知道
Yes I know.
她是大萧条时期长大的
She was raised in the Depression.
每个人都在帮忙抚养别人
everyone helped raise everyone.
整个街坊抚养所有的孩子
You know, the whole neighborhood raised the kids.
对不起
Sorry.
我们来做心理治疗吧
Can we do therapy?
天啊 我现在不想做心理治疗
Jesus, I don't want to do therapy right now
- 来角色扮演      - 求你了 别
- Let's role play.        - Please no.
我来当你妈妈 你可以说说你想对她说的话
I'll be your mom, and you can tell her what you wanna tell her.
来吧
Just do it.
- 我不想跟我妈说话      - 你会对她说什么
- I don't want to talk to my mom.        - What would you say to her?
好吧
Okay.
我不需要你的帮助 妈
I don't need your help, Mom.
我自己可以的
I've got it.
我没事
I'm okay.
我需要设计一个故事
I, I'm gonna need a story.
什么
What?
一个故事
A story.
- 什么意思      - 比如...
- What do you mean?        - Like...
这么一个故事
A story.
我...
Where...
只是一个普通的女人
I'm just a normal woman.
然后...
and...
你是一个摄影师
you're a photographer.
你在给我拍照 但是...
And you're photographing me, but...
当你拍照的时候
While you are doing it...
你情难自已 开始触碰我
You can't help yourself and you start touching me.
然后...
And...
你抚摸我
You touch me.
然后...
And you...
你说
Say...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
真的要这样吗
Really?
我不能就是我自己吗
I...can't just be myself?
不行
No.
- 好了 那我们就...      - 很高兴认识你
- Okay, so...should we just...?        - Nice to meet you.
噢 你好 我要看镜头吗
Oh, hi. Do I just look in the camera?
- 还是看旁边？      - 先这样吧
- Or should I look off to the side?        - Let's start that way...
- 看着镜头      - 好的
- Looking in the camera.        - Okay.
我要微笑吗
Should I smile?
你喜欢微笑吗
Do you like to smile?
- 喜欢      - 可以
- Yeah.        - Okay.
好的
Okay.
你拍了 我还以为你会先数1 2 3
Oh, you took it. I thought you are gonna say like 1, 2, 3...
- 不是 我只是在等待那个时刻      - 好的
- No. I just wait for the moment.        - Okay.
我得调整点东西
I just have to fix something.
这里
It's right here.
- 不好意思      - 没关系的
- I am sorry.        - No, it's alright.
我不介意
I don't mind.
我只是以前没拍过
I've just never done this before.
所以...
So...
我还有点紧张
I'm still little bit nervous.
但是...
But...
- 我可以换个发型      - 艾比
- I can wear my hair differently.        - Abbie.
嗯？
Yeah?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我和朱莉从小就是朋友
Julie and I have been friends since we were little.
朱莉・哈姆林 生于1962年
她总说她是个自我毁灭的人
She likes to say she's self-destructive.
她母亲是一名心理医生
Her mother is a therapist.
我们以前常常说话 那时...
We used to talk and I...
我还比较了解你 我很担心你
had a better sense of what's going on with you. i'm worried
她让朱莉参加她的青少年小组谈话
She makes Julie attend her teen group sessions.
有没有这种可能
How about the possibility?
你无意间选择了
That you're choosing boys who are inappropriate?
不合适的男孩子
Unconsciously.
她母亲再婚以后 朱莉变了
When her mother remarried, Julie changed.
当她同母异父且妹妹阿曼达一出生就得了脑瘫时
When her half sister Amanda was born...
她的变化更大了
with Cerebral Palsy, she changed more.
你明白我说什么吗
You know what I mean.
你这样看起来好漂亮 整张脸美得冒泡
Wow. It looks really pretty on you, it just makes your whole face pop.
就像清新的苏打水一样
Like soda pop.
她开始放纵自己
She started fooling around.
开始溜进我家
She started sneaking into my house.
在我家过夜
Sleeping over.
- 你为什么那么做      - 因为我疯了
- Why'd you do it?        - Because I'm crazy.
你宁可自己疯了
You wish you were crazy.
帮我挠挠
Scratch me.
我们应该沿着海岸往北走
We should go up the coast somewhere.
就你和我
Just me and you.
朱莉在拉昆布雷商场工作
Julie works at the La Cumbre Plaza mall.
春雨系列的主要成分是肉桂 薄荷 铃兰和玫瑰
Spring rain features cinnamon, jasmine, lily-of-the-valley and rose.
性是一种承诺
Sex is commitment.
《永远》 作者 朱迪・布鲁姆 1975年
一旦到达这个阶段 就不可能回到牵手之交
once you're there, you can't go back to holding hands.
一旦你在心理和生理上献出了自己
and once you give yourself both mentally and physically...
你就会变得极其脆弱
well, you're completely vulnerable.
他只关心他的新婚妻子和她的生日
All he cares about is his new wife and her birthday.
以及与她和她的家人共度圣诞
And Christmas with her and her family.
以及邀请她全家参加所有的...
And inviting all of her family to all of ...
春雨系列的主要成分是肉桂 茉莉 铃兰和玫瑰
Spring rain features cinnamon, jasmine, lily-of-the-valley and rose.
所有关于爱情的误解里
Of all the misconceptions about love...
《少有人走的路》 作者 M・斯科特・派克 1978年
最强大最有说服力的是
the most powerful and persuasive is the belief that
人们以为陷入爱情就是爱情
falling in love is love.
或者至少是爱情的一种表现
or at least one of the manifestations of love.
爱情应该是你感受到的一种感觉
Love is supposed to be a feeling that you feel.
人们说他们陷入爱情
People say that they're falling in love...
但他们并非真的陷入了爱情
but they're not actually falling in love.
那只是你自己感受到的与别人的错误联系
It's a fake connection that you feel with someone.
婚姻永远不应该存在
and marriage should never happen.
你早该去死了 该是你承受这些的
YOU SHOULD HAVE DIED, IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN YOU.
去死吧
DIE!
嗨 朱莉
Hey, Julie.
- 嗨      - 你好
- Hey.        - Hi.
进来吧
So come on in.
没事的 进来吧
It's Okay, come in.
他还没起床呢
He's not up yet.
他昨天回来得挺晚的
He got in kinda late.
你可以帮我把这些东西端进去吗
You wanna help me bring this stuff in?
杰米还好吗
So is Jamie okay?
还好
Yeah.
他没什么事
He's okay.
他昨晚回来的时候我听到了
I heard by him come in last night.
我还没睡
I was awake.
好吧
Right.
我就是 睡不着
Yea, I was just, couldn't sleep.
等着听到他回来
so I was, you know, listening for him.
演出怎么样
How was the show?
挺好的
Good.
下次你出远门的时候
Next time you take a trip,
提前告诉我一声 好吗
just let me know, okay?
这样我晚饭就不会做多了
I won't make too much dinner.
来一起记股票吗
Hey, do the stocks with me?
可以
Yeah.
好的 IBM
Okay, IBM.
IBM 69.73美元
IBM, $69.73
施乐
Xerox.
你还好吗
You okay?
施乐 53.92美元
Xerox, $53.92.
- 住手      - 好的 53.92美元
- Stop.        - Okay, $ 53.92.
听着
Listen.
艾比今天要去见医生 我没法陪她去
Abbie has her appointment today and I can't be here...
我得去上班
And I have to go to work.
所以我希望在她回来的时候
So I was hoping that maybe you could be here.
你能在这儿
When she gets back.
可能她会需要精神支撑
In case she needs support.
她正在承受很多东西
She is going through a lot.
好的 万一...
Okay, What if it's..
有坏消息或是什么的要怎么办
Like bad news or something?
你可以处理的 如果你不能
Well, you can handle it or if you can't...
你总得学着去处理
You have to start somewhere.
男人总是觉得他们得
Men always feel like they have to
为女人弥补些什么
fix things for women...
但他们其实什么也没做
But they are not doing anything.
有些事情是无法弥补的
But some things just can't be fixed.
你只需要在场就好了
Just be there...
不知怎么 这对你们来说显得很难
Somehow, that's hard for all of you.
妈 我不是"所有男人"
Mom, I'm not "all men".
好吗 我就是我
Okay? I'm just me.
好吧 也对也不对
Well, yes and no.
要是我得做化疗
What if I have to have full on chemo?
或者子宫切除要怎么办
Or get a hysterectomy?
你知道那是什么吗
Do you know what that is?
听着 我应该干脆就陪你一起去
Look,I should just go with you. You know, I mean..
你妈妈确实叫我和你分享我的生活
Your mom did tell me to share my life with you.
是啊 我知道
Yeah I know.
你不必...
You don't...
不用在意 她是...
Don't worry about it, she just...
大萧条时期长大的
She's from The Depression.
是啊
Yeah.
这是好消息 艾比
It's good news， Abbie.
没有恶性细胞了
There were no malignant cells.
你的切片检查结果是良性的
Your biopsy is benign.
那...以后呢
And...in the future?
手术使你的子宫肌层受损
There was damage to the muscle wall from the surgery.
导致子宫颈机能不全
You have an incompetent cervix.
机能不全？
Incompetent?
妊娠时 不足以支撑到
It may not be strong enough...
妊娠期满
to go full term during pregnancy.
当胎儿长大
As the baby grows...
子宫颈扩张
the cervix widens.
如果子宫颈变松弛 就可能会过早张开
If it's weakened, it's likely to open prematurely.
我会没事的
I'm gonna be OK.
他说我很可能不能生孩子了
He said that I probably can't have kids.
生下杰米是不是
Was having Jamie like...
你一生中发生过的最重要的事
the biggest thing that ever happened to you?
我想是吧
I guess so.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事
No.
你能撑过去的
You'll get through this.
你会撑过去的
You will get through it.
你可以的
You will do it.
这是最艰难的时刻 接下来会发生的事是
This is the really hard part. And then what happens is,
在艰难的时刻之后 一切都会好起来
there's a hard part and then it gets better.
然后又会变糟 不过不用在意
And then it gets hard again, but never mind.
我不应该告诉你后面那部分的
I should not have told you that part.
我应该说 一切都会好起来的...就这样
I should've just said it gets better and then...That's it.
但是...
But...
你养鸟？
You got birds?
养鸟没关系吧
Is that ok?
没事
Yes.
你给他们取名了吗
So did you name them?
还没有
Not yet.
一只雄鸟 一只雌鸟
They are a boy and a girl.
而且它们是终身一夫一妻的
And, that, they are monogamous for life.
所以...
So...
如果其中一只死了 另一只...
If one of them dies, then the other one...
一周之后也会死去
He will die like a week later.
墨西哥国王及王后
叫马克西米利安和卡洛塔怎么样
How about Maximilian and Carlotta?
我...
Right, I...
觉得它们配得上高贵的名字
You know, they deserve something grand.
他们终身都是一夫一妻呢
they're gonna be monogamous their whole lives.
是吧
Right?
马克西和卡洛塔真是好名字
Max and Carlotta are really good names.
所以
So...
你陪她去看了医生 还在那等她
You went to the doctor's and you waited with her.
是啊
Yeah.
但是我让你在这儿等着
But I told you to wait here.
我...呃...
I..um...
我想我最好还是
I thought it would be better to...
和她一起去 在那儿等着
go and really be there.
她很沮丧
She is really upset.
你应该也承受了不少吧
That must have been a lot to deal with.
我还好
I'm fine.
我没事
I'm good.
我...
I...
我学到了很多
I learned a lot
阿比盖尔・波特
Abigail Porter.
女性在家就能安全快捷方便地
Home pregnancy tests that...
进行的验孕测试
Women can do safely and easily.
这是女性掌控自己人生的
A small revolution for...
一个小型革命
women seeking to take control of their lives.
这是什么东西
What the fuck is this?
验孕的
It's a pregnancy test.
艾比的医生说
Abbie's doctors said that...
她生不了孩子
She wouldn't be able to have kids.
她干嘛带你一起去
Why'd she take you?
- 就这些了?      - 对
- Is that all of it?        - Yeah.
好多啊
That's a lot.
现在干嘛
Now what?
摇晃十秒
Shake for 10 seconds.
好了
Okay.
静置两小时
Leave undisturbed for 2 hours.
两小时？
2 hours?
这上面是这么写的
that's what it says.
好了 如果出现一个环 结果就是阳性的
Okay. If it appears then you're positive,
如果没有出现 那就是阴性的
And if no ring appears here then the test is negative.
那这两小时我们干嘛
What do we do for two hours?
男人不那样抽烟 不要那样拿
Guy's don't smoke like that. Don't hold it like that.
要...
Like...
这样
This.
夹在两根手指中间
Between your two fingers.
- 这样？      - 是的 这样好多了
- That?        - Yes, that's better.
好 现在 走路
Okay now, walk,
拿着烟很酷地走路
do like a cool cigarette walk.
男人不会看起来像是在想他们看起来是什么样的
Guys aren't supposed look like they're thinking about what they look like.
看我的
Watch me.
看到了吗
See?
抽烟很恶心
Smoking is gross.
不 不恶心
No, it's not.
会让你得癌症
Gives you cancer.
这只是我的观点 我认为坚强...
This is just my opinion, I think being strong..
是最重要的品质
..is the most important quality.
不是脆弱 不是敏感
It's not being vulnerable, It's not being sensitive.
甚至不是诚实 也不是快乐
It's not even... Honestly, it's not even being happy.
关乎力量
It's about strength.
和你忍受其他情绪的能力
And your durability against the other emotions.
没有环
No ring.
- 嘿      - 嘿
- Hey.        - Hey.
谢谢你陪我去
Thanks for going with me.
没事
Yeah, totally.
我做了这个给你
I made you this.
- 一个合集磁带      - 没错
- It's a mixed tape.         - Yep.
这里面的几首歌 是我觉得
These are bunch of songs, that I think my life...
如果我在年少的时候就能听到它们
would have been better if they would have been around.
我的人生会比现在更好
When I was a teenager.
所以我希望 如果你现在就能听到这些歌
So I'm hoping, that if you listen to them, now...
你会成为我所期望成为的那个
you'll be a happier and more realized person...
更快乐 更丰满的人
than I could ever hope to be.
艾比・波特 生于1955年
从那晚起
From that night on...
艾比开始和我无话不说
Abbie started telling me everything.
她在圣巴巴拉长大
She grew up in Santa Barbara.
那里的每个人都很快乐
Where everyone is happy.
但这让她很抓狂
but that just made her feel crazy.
1973年 她搬到了纽约
In 1973 she moved to New York City...
进入艺术学校学习
and went to Art school.
纽约让她有同样的感觉
New York City made her feel same.
她那时一团糟
She was so fucked up.
后来 她爱上了摄影
She fell in love with photography.
她学会了难过的时候就跳舞
She learned to dance when she got sad.
她看了《天外来客》
She saw "The Man Who Fell to Earth"...
把自己的头发染成了红色
And dyed her hair red.
我知道了该如何被
I figured out how to be looked at ...
男人欣赏 以及...
by men, and...
如何让他们
How to make them...
既兴奋又难受
excited and uncomfortable.
我很混蛋 很愤怒
I am so cocky and I was so angry.
也很快乐
And I was so happy.
她爱上了她的老师
She fell in love with her teacher.
- 然后她去了计生所堕胎      - 艾比盖尔・波特
- Then she went to Planned Parenthood.        - Abigail Porter.
她的朋友没法承受她得癌症的事实
Her friends couldn't deal with her having cancer.
所以她回家找她妈妈去了
So she went home to her mom.
嗨 妈
Hey Mom.
盖尔 你怀艾比的时候
Gail, did you ever take DES?
服用过已烯雌酚吗
When you were pregnant with Abe?
是的
Yes.
怀艾比之前我流产过两次
I had two miscarriages before Abbie,
医生建议我服用的
the doctor told me to take it.
己烯雌酚是种助孕药物
DES was a fertility medication.
医生会开这种药给女性
Doctors prescribed it to women.
后来他们发现
Later they found out that the daughters...
那些用药者的女儿
of the women who took it...
会得宫颈癌
Got cervical cancer.
我不知道你流过产
I didn't know that you had miscarriages.
在她母亲发现这是她服用药物造成的之后
When her mom found out it was because she took that drug...
她不愿再提这件事
she wouldn't talk about it.
而且艾比做的任何事
And everything Abbie did
都会让她恼火不已
made her mad.
所以艾比换了个地方住
So Abbie looked for another place to live.
-嗨      -你好
- Hi.        - Hello.
她租了楼上的房间
And she started renting the room upstairs.
我叫艾比
I'm Abbie.
然后在新闻社找了份工作
And she got a job at the news press.
- 嗨 多萝西娅      - 嗨 查理
- Hi Dorothea.        - Hi, Charlie.
嗨
Hi.
你想出去玩玩吗
You wanna go out sometime?
喝点东西？
Get a drink?
好啊
Yeah.
什么情况 查理
What the heck, Charlie?
当然可以
Sure.
好呀
okay.
我之前还不确定
I wasn't sure.
怎么了
What?
有些家伙以为你是女同志
Some of the guys thought you are a lesbian.
你懂的
You know.
如果你是的话 我也没问题
Which I don't have a problem if you are.
可你不是
But you are not.
你知道我不是的
You know I'm not.
那我们还能出去吗
Shall we go out then?
好啊 可以
Okay, yeah.
当然 你想什么时候再来我家吃晚餐吗
Sure. You wanna come to dinner at my house again sometime?
很好
Good...
我们就这么做吧
We could do that.
可恶
Shit!
朱莉
Julie.
真的没有什么
It's really, it's nothing.
我只在那过夜过几次而已
I just end up there sometimes.
你们都做些什么
What do you guys do?
我就睡觉
I just sleep.
我们会聊天
We talk.
能给来我一根吗
Can I have one?
不行 抽烟对你有害
No, they are really bad for you.
可你自己也抽个不停
You smoke all the time.
我开始抽烟的时候烟还不是有害的 只是为了时髦
You know, when I started they weren't bad for you.They were just stylish.
可以说是很前卫
Sort of edgy, so...
所以对我来说不一样
It's different for me.
行吧
Okay.
你很擅长隐藏秘密啊
You're good at hiding stuff, huh?
我妈称之为情绪划分
My mom calls it compartmentalizing.
显然我经常这么做
Apparently I do that a lot.
你在帮助他吗
Are you helping him?
我正在努力
I am trying.
真的吗
Really?
那你呢
What about you?
你想过你对他的影响吗
Have you thought about your impact on him?
这都是和母亲有关系的
It's always about the mother.
比如说离开他爸之后 你向前看了吗
Like, do you think you've moved on, since his dad?
你知道你才不是什么心理医生吧
You know that you're not actually a therapist?
我交往过几个男人 好吗
I've had new guys, okay?
没一个是合适的
No one appropriate.
合适的？
Appropriate?
都是些你不愿为之冒险的男人
Guys you're not going to risk anything with.
甚至是你都不喜欢的男人
Men you don't even really like.
听着 你才十七岁好吗
Listen, you're 17, Okay?
也许你根本看不出我真心喜欢的那些男人
Maybe you don't know what's good about these guys.
身上的优点
That I really like.
我说的是你
I'm talking about you.
你好像从来都不投入
You never seem into it.
除了对威廉
Except for with William.
可是
But...
他不合适
He is inappropriate.
好吧 天哪
Okay, Jesus.
没错
Yeah.
要找到我喜欢的人很难
It's hard to find someone that I like.
我曾经有过机会 两次
I had my chance, twice.
但是结果都未能如愿
But that part of life just didn't work out for me.
- 再见      - 再见
- Bye.        - Bye.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我出去办了点事
I had some errands.
你把整个表都填完了?
You did the whole list?
你知道每只股票吗
You know all the stocks?
对啊
Yeah.
IBM写到下面去了
IBM is down.
抱歉 我下次会改过来的
Sorry, I'll fix it next time.
你干得不错
Good job on that.
威廉
William.
在
Yes.
你觉得我在停滞不前吗
Do I seem stuck to you?
你指什么
How do you mean?
我应该不知道吧 对吗
Well, I guess I wouldn't know, Would I?
- 艾比      - 嗯？
- Abbie.        - Yes?
我们今晚出去玩吧
Let's go out tonight.
我想看看这个现代世界
I want to see this modern world.
我能一起去吗
Can I go?
我知道能不能在这找到合适的男人
I don't know if I'm going to find an appropriate man here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是什么
What was that?
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
在搞清楚什么意思之前别乱亲女人
Don't kiss a woman if you unless you know what you mean by it.
你不是在和艾比上床吗
Aren't you sleeping with Abbie?
那不是认真的 只是...
That's not something serious, is...
那为什么还这么做
Then why do it?
那是1979年 我55岁
It's 1979, I am 55 years old...
这是我儿子所笃信的
This is what my son believes in.
就是这种人
These people.
顶着这种发型 穿着这种衣服
With this hair... And these clothes.
摆出这种姿势 发出这种声响
Making these gestures, making these sounds.
那是1979年 我55岁
It's 1979 and I am 55 years old...
在1999年 我会因为抽烟死于癌症
and in 1999 I'll die of cancer from smoking.
嘿
Hey!
- 你要走了吗      - 对
- You going?        - Yeah.
帮我个忙 照顾好艾比
Do me a favor, just take care of Abbie.
他们没有意识到这是朋克的终结
They don't know this is the end of punk.
他们也没想到里根会上台
They don't know that Reagan's coming.
难以想象这些孩子会停止幻想核战
It's impossible to imagine that kids will stop dreaming about nuclear war.
而对气候危机提心吊胆
And have nightmares about the weather.
难以想象的还有艾滋病
It's impossible to imagine HIV.
以及滑板的技巧
what will happen with skateboard tricks.
还有互联网
The Internet...
- 你玩得开心吗      - 嗯 挺好玩的
- Did you have a good time?        - Yeah, it was interesting.
- 艾比有你的电话 对吗      - 对
- So Abbie has your number, right?        - Yeah.
- 改天请你来吃晚饭      - 好呀
- Give you a call for dinner.        - I would like that.
孩子
Kid...
很晚了
It's late...
那儿怎么样
How was it?
让人宛如新生
It was life changing.
在我死前 我会为千禧虫危机的到来做准备
Before I die, I will prepare for Y2K.
我在车库备好罐头食物和水
I will put canned food and water in the garage.
我把价值一万六千美元的金币
I put 16 thousand dollars worth of gold coins...
存进蒙特西托银行的保险箱里
into a safe deposit box at the Bank of Montecito.
我在新千年之前就死了
I died before the New Year...
海豚型气球在我头顶飘来飘去
Dolphin-shaped balloons floated over my head.
人们用音响播放着路易斯・阿姆斯特朗的音乐
They were playing Louis Armstrong on a Boombox.
Louis Armstrong - Basin Street Blues?
杰米？
Jamie?
抱歉 你醒着吗
Sorry, are you awake...?
我只是想告诉你 你得离开这个地方
I just wanted to tell you that you have to get out of this town.
如果你想要有机会...
If you want to have any chance...
过上有趣的生活
of an interesting life moving forward.
发生什么了
What happened?
抱歉 妈呀
Sorry, shit!
我们不做爱
We don't have sex.
我只是在这睡觉
I just sleep here.
好吧
Okay...
- 我能躺下吗      - 我们正在睡觉
- Can I lay down?        - We were sleeping.
- 忍忍吧      - 没关系的 我就想要...
- Just get over.        - It' Okay, I'm just gonna talk...
和杰米说几句话
to Jamie for a second...
莉奈特・温特斯朝我吐了口水
So Lynette Winters spit on me.
然后我揍了她
So then I hit her.
- 她为什么朝你吐口水      - 因为我朝她吐口水了
- Why'd she spit on you?        - Because I spit on her.
我就快要去纽约了
Right before I was going to New York
我心想我再也不回来了
and I thought I was never gonna come back.
当时觉得全身无比释放
It felt very liberating at the time.
最后我不知怎地还砸烂了一把椅子
And somehow I ended up breaking a chair.
- 嗨 朱利安 不好意思      - 你没事吧
- Hey Julian, I'm sorry.        - You okay?
嗯嗯 我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
然后威廉告诉我
And then William told me...
他不想再和我上床了
he didn't wanna sleep with me anymore.
你在说什么 我又不喜欢你
What are you saying? I don't like you...
我不喜欢你 我不喜欢…
I don't like you. I don't like...
我只…
Just...
我只要跟杰米说几句话
I'm just gonna talk to Jamie for a second...
你不能让她睡在这
You can not let her sleep here.
如果她不和你上床 这样对你不好
If she's not having sex with you, it's dis-empowering.
还有 你得在去墨镜店工作前
Also you need to get out of this town before you start working.
就离开这个地方
at a sunglasses shop...
对你来说也是一样的
and it goes for you too.
杰米 给你几本书
Jamie, here is some books...
我在女权主义课上拿的
from a feminism class I took...
我想它们能帮助你
I thought it would be helpful for you,
了解女性的视角
to get a woman's perspective.
- 你的嘴唇怎么了      - 我打架了
- What happened to your lip?        - I got in a fight.
- 什么      - 我打了一架
- What?        - There was a fight.
当时很荒唐
It was, it was ridiculous...
等等 这是《身体与自我》吗
Hold on, is that "Our Bodies Our Selves"?
这本书很不错
This is a really good book...
有一章节特别棒
There is a very good chapter...
关于家中分娩的
On home births.
家中分娩遏制了婴儿的成长人格
Home births actually stunts the baby's growth personality.
- 成长人格是个什么东西      - 是个真的术语
- What is a growth personality?        - It's a real term.
谁能知道对于新生儿来说
Who knows what it means for a new born...
看到木质的墙壁
to see wood walls, and...
和铺上地毯的地板
carpeted floors and to smell...
闻到人类真实的气息
real human smells and to feel...
感受到羊毛 棉质 法兰绒的触感
wool and cotton and flannel clothes...
而不是死气沉沉的 苍白的
instead of starchy, white...
无味的东西意味着什么呢
deodorized...
对我来说 那就像… 还有什么呢
To me, that meant like… and what else?
Neu! - Lila Engel (Lila Angel)?
《高潮的法则》 作者 苏珊・莱登 1970年
女性的性行为
Women's sexuality,
由男性定义并取悦男性
defined by men to benefit men.
一直被轻视 扭曲 压抑和控制
has been downgraded and perverted, repressed and channeled.
在解剖学上 所有性高潮都以阴蒂为中心
Anatomically, all orgasms are centered in the clitoris.
通过人工对阴蒂直接触压
whether they result from direct manual pressure applied to the clitoris.
或是通过间接触压…
indirect pressure resulting from...
我狠狠地操了海瑟 她高潮了三次
I fucked Heather so hard, she came like three times.
- 你怎么刺激她的阴蒂的      - 用我的鸡巴
- How did you stimulate her clitoris?        - With my dick.
女性需要对阴蒂的直接刺激
Women need direct clitoral stimulation.
例如用手指或振动棒等等
Like with fingers, or vibrators, or something.
她很可能是装的
She probably faked it.
女人常常假装高潮
women fake it all the time.
传声头乐队就是一群基佬
Talking Heads are a bunch of fags.
其实他们乐队里还有个女生
Actually there's a girl in their band...
而且她在和鼓手交往 所以...
And she's dating the drummer, so...
她叫简妮尔
Her name is Janior...
叫你乱讲话 臭基佬
Fuckin' around faggot.
所以是为了什么打架
So, what was the fight about?
刺激阴蒂
Clitoral stimulation.
为什么你们要为此打架
Why do you need to fight about that?
我不知道 我想做个好男人
I don't know, I wanna be a good guy...
好吗 我就想…
Okay. I just wanna...
能够满足女人
be able to satisfy a woman.
孩子 我相信你会的
Kid, I'm sure you will.
妈的
Shit!
文艺基佬
杰米
Jamie!
这一点都不酷
That's not cool...
对 马特就是这么叫我的 因为我喜欢传声头乐队
Yeah, That's what Matt called me. For liking the talking heads.
- 黑旗又是什么      - 一支硬核乐队
- And what is Black Flag?        - It's a hardcore band.
所以...
So...
喜欢黑旗的人都会讨厌传声头乐队
The people who love Black Flag, hate the Talking Heads.
什么东西
What?
朋克界内部不太和
The punk scene is very divisive.
嘿
Hey!
你们都很前卫啊 是不是
You are all so advanced, aren't you?
下次有男生跟你聊他们的性事
The next time a guy tells you a sex story...
你只需要同意他说的每句话
You just have to agree with everything he says...
假装他是对的就行了
and act like it's right.
哪怕是错的 因为他们不喜欢被反驳
Even if it's not, because they don't wanna be contradicted.
他们只想活在自己幻想的世界里
They just wanna to live in their fantasy lands.
你都是怎么处理
How are you dealing?
每件事的
With everything.
无论你如何想象你未来的人生
Whatever you think your life is going to be like,
你要明白 现实总会完全不同
just know, it's not going to be anything like that.
好吧
Right...
带我去那个酒吧吧
Take me to that club.
今晚吗
Tonight?
- 嘿      - 嗨
- Hey.        - Hi..
哇 你看起来真美 你们要去哪
Wow, you look amazing... Where are you going?
我们想出去玩 可以吗
We're just gonna go out... Is that okay?
当然可以了 要去哪
Oh yeah, of course... And where to?
就出去外面
Just going out.
- 再见      - 再见
- Bye.        - Bye.
把它藏起来
Hide it there.
嘿 能给我瓶啤酒吗
Hey, can I have a beer?
现在说 “我喜欢年纪比我大的女人”
Now say I'm into older women.
- 什么      - 快说
- What?        - Just say it.
我喜欢年纪比我大的女人
I'm into older women.
你几岁了
How old are you?
年龄是中产阶级才有的概念
Age is a bourgeois construct.
回答得不错
It's a good answer.
- 年龄是...      - 好了好了 可以了
- Age is...        - Ok, ok, you've got it.
听着 现在如果她问你太多问题
So now, if she asks too many questions...
你就尽量少回答 好吗
You just say as little as possible, okay?
现在让我看看你最深不可测的表情
Now show me your most inscrutable face.
我其实不会主动去挑...女人
I don't really make choices… About women...
她们会…
They just...
她们会自己送上门
They come to you.
那...你本来可以找到更好的
That's… You could have more than that.
那你呢 为什么…
But what about you? Why...?
我的意思是 杰米的父亲怎么了
I mean, what happened to Jamie's dad?
他只是变得和我以为的不一样了
He just didn't turn out like I thought he would.
我想也是
I guess that happens...
他肯定还是有些优点的
There must've been something good about him.
- 他是左撇子      - 就这样？
- He was left handed?        - That's it?
就这样？
That's it?
然后我是右撇子 所以每天早上
And I was right handed. And so... In the morning...
我们会一起看股票报告 然后…
We would look at the stock reports together and...
他可以边用左手写字 边用右手挠我的背
He could write with his left hand and scratch my back with his right.
- 就是这样      - 我特别喜欢
- And that's it!        - I loved that.
你冥想过吗
Do you ever meditate?
我感受空气 感受空气的寒冷 穿过我的鼻子
I feel the air... coldness of the air. Goes through my nose...
我要做的就是...
All I'm really doing is...
将注意力集中到我的呼吸上
Bringing my attention back to my breath.
所以在我吸气时
So when I take a breathe in...
我会感觉到
There is a feeling...
空气流入
Air going in...
空气流出
Air going out...
感觉真好
It's a good feeling.
没关系 我只是要…
It's okay..good... I'm just gonna...
继续
Go ahead...
我只是想抽个烟
I'm just gonna smoke...
我听着呢
I'm listening...
- 我想要和你同步      - 你真的是...
- I wanna get on the same page.        - You are such...
你是怎么变成现在这个样子的
How did you get to be this person that you are?
你真的很不同寻常
It's so... You're so unusual.
威廉的父亲在克利夫兰开了一家汽车维修店
William's dad managed an auto repair shop in Cleveland.
他一直很懂引擎
Engines always made sense to him.
他本想坚持读完大学 可是付不起学费
He tried to put himself through college, but couldn't afford it.
他在1963年遇见了特丽莎
He met Theresa in 1963,
她聪明勇敢 经济条件也好
she was smart, brave, better off,...
他们相爱了 一起搬去奥克兰
they were in love. They moved to Oakland,
塞瓦斯托波尔: 前苏联克里米亚半岛西南岸港市
然后去了塞瓦斯托波尔的一个公社
Then, to a commune in Sevastopol.
我学着变成他们那样
Well I learned to be like them.
你懂吗
You know?
结果这比我想象中简单得多
As it turns out, it was a lot easier than I thought it would be.
但那不是真正的我 我这么做是
but it wasn't really me. I was doing it for...
为了不失去特丽莎
So that I wouldn't lose Theresa.
于是他变得看起来像他们 说话也像他们
He started looking like them, talking like them...
但他们让他觉得自己苍老 无知和贫穷
but they made him feel old and uneducated and poor.
特丽莎开始觉得...
Theresa started thinking...
威廉保守刻板而且占有欲很强 便离开了他
William was uptight and possessive and she left him.
在特丽莎之后
After Theresa...
什么样的女人我都可以
Women didn't have to look one way or the other.
不必是特定的类型
Or be a certain way.
我觉得我只要...
I think that I just...
我只想赢得她们 这样我就不至于寂寞了
I want to win them over so that I won't be lonely.
- 你住这里吗      - 对的
- You live here?        - I do.
但是我一旦得到他们
But, once I have them...
就不知道该对她们怎么办了
I don't really know what to do with them.
- 你等会想做点什么      - 睡觉
- You want to do something later?        - Sleep.
我该走了
I should go.
他的爱好是制作陶碗
What he likes is making bowls...
那时他闻起来不再是机油和润滑油的味道了
He doesn't smell like oil and grease...
他的手也不再像是汽修工的粗手了
his hands don't look like a dumb mechanic's hands.
我先用了一段时间的小碗 然后我觉得我需要...
I've been using smaller bowls for a while, then I was kinda feeling like I need…
然后等它变得干点之后…
And when it gets little bit drier...
它很漂亮
It's beautiful.
什么情况
What?
是你修好的嘛
Did you fix it?
这个嘛 可能吧
Well, maybe.
它有部分是大众汽车的
It's part of Volkswagen now.
我临时改装了一下
I had to improvise.
那你要怎么认识别人呢
And how you're gonna get to know a person way over there?
- 我该怎么做      - 你就随便聊聊
- What am I supposed to do?        - Just make a little small talk.
介绍你自己 邀请她跳舞
Introduce yourself... ask her to dance...
- 好吧 你好 我是威廉      - 你好
- Okay, hello I am William...        - Hello...
你好 我住在你楼下
Hello... I live downstairs...
- 喔对      - 和车住一块
- Yeah.        - With the cars...
- 你愿意和我跳舞吗      - 当然
- Would you like to dance with me?        - Yes, sure.
好吧
Okay.
伸出你的手来 然后把另一只手放在这里
Put your hand out right. Put the other hand here and just be there...
- 她想要的就是陪伴      - 喔 好的
- All she wants is a little company.        - Oh good...
很好
That's nice.
David Bowie- DJ?
我觉得我可以理解你
I feel like I understand you.
我们应该逃离这里 就你和我 你懂吗
We should get away from here. It's just me and you, you know?
沿着海边往北 去某个地方独处
Go up the coast... Be alone somewhere.
杰米 你爱的是朱莉
Jamie, You are in love with Julie...
你不能这样任她摆布
You can't let it push you around.
你得告诉她你想要的
You have to tell her what you want.
要是你那时候在听的话...
If you were to listen to it...
那是什么意思 文艺基佬
What does that mean... Art Fag?
我的意思是 那是...
I mean, what is...?
如果你从社会学的角度来看待这件事
If you would've think about it from more like a sociological perspective.
那词是从哪来的 文艺基佬
Where does that come from? Art fag.
- 那到底是什么      - 艾比知道它是什么
- What is that?        - Abbie understands it.
艾比才不知道 她只不过是身在其中
Abbie does not understand it, she's just a part of it.
Black Flag- Nervous Breakdown?
我们不必喜欢它
We don't need to like it.
好吧 他在说什么
Okay, what is he saying?
把头靠在我肩上
Head on my shoulders...
- 狂怒起来      - 什么
- going berserk.        - What?
- 这有意思吗      - 我不知道
- Is that interesting?        - I don't know.
我也不知道
I don't know either.
我觉得我们可能想太多了
I think we're maybe over-thinking this.
我们听听文艺基佬吧
Let's try the Art Fag one.
文艺基佬来了
Here come the Art Fags.
Talking Heads - The Big Country?
好的
Oh yeah.
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
就是这样
That's it.
我觉得我们是文艺基佬类型的
I guess we're more the art fag types.
我喜欢
I like that.
过来 你这个深不可测的男孩
Come here, you inscrutable boy.
我给他喝了啤酒
I gave him beer and then I...
然后教他用语言诱惑女人
taught him how to verbally seduce women.
然后…
And...
我们喝醉了开车 但我停下来了
we drove drunk, but I stopped that.
然后他亲了翠西 然后我们走回家了
and then he kissed Trish… and then we walked home.
你不生气吗
You're not mad?
你生气了...
You are mad...
你能看到他在外面的世界为人的样子
You get to see him out in the world as a person.
我永远看不到
I never will.
等等…
Just...
看这个
There.
不敢相信艾比把这本书给了你
I can't believe Abbie gave you this book.
书很有趣
It's interesting.
那是什么感觉
What's it like?
- 对女孩儿来说...      - 什么
- For girls...        - What?
性?
Sex?
高潮
Orgasms.
你真想知道那是什么感觉
Do you really want to know what it's like?
对
Yeah.
我没有过
I don't have them.
什么
What?
我朋友也没有过
None of my friends do.
- 那你们为什么还做      - 因为别的原因
- So why do you do it?        - There's other reasons.
你知道吗 比如他注视你的样子
You know, like the way that he looks at you...
他们到某个点都会有一点渴求的样子
the way they all get a little desperate at some point.
还有他们发出的小呻吟
And the little sounds that they make.
还有他们的身体...
And their bodies...
因为你无法确切地知道他们看起来会是什么样子
Cause you don't exactly know what they're gonna look like..
闻起来也好 摸起来也罢
Or smell or feel like...
你做了才知道
Until you do it.
但是啊…
But yeah...
半数我都后悔了
Half the time I regret it.
那你为什么还做
Then why do you do it?
因为还有一半我不后悔
Cause half the time I don't regret it.
《活着和过时是痛苦的：衰老的女人》
作者 佐伊・莫斯 1970年
我很合群 对他人感兴趣
I am gregarious...interested in others.
我也聪明
and I think intelligence…
我想要的只是了解他人并且...
All I ask is to get to know people and...
让他们有兴趣了解我
to have them interested in knowing me.
我不确定自己是否会再次结婚
I doubt whether I would marry again and...
去和另一个人如此近距离生活
live that close to another individual.
但我总是受人忽视
But I remain invisible.
当你看着我的时候 连一分钟都不要假装
Don't pretend for a minute, as you look at me
以为我不如你一般鲜活
that I'm not as alive as you are.
我也不要因为你给我强加的标签
and I do not suffer from the category...
而受罪
to which you are forcing me...
我觉得脱光了之后 我比我前夫更迷人
I think stripped down I look more attractive than my ex-husband...
但在生理上和社会上我都过时了
But I am sexually and socially obsolete.
他却没有
And he is not.
现在我有能力接受人们真实的样子
I have a capacity now for taking people as they are.
这是我二十多岁时做不到的
which I lacked at twenty.
我半数时间都能够达到高潮
I reach orgasm in half the time...
我也知道如何取悦
and I know how to please...
然而我却不敢向一个男人表示
Yet I do not even dare show a man...
我觉得他有多迷人
that I find him attractive.
如果我这么做了 他可能会觉得像是我冒犯了他一样
If I do so, he may react as if I had insulted him.
我就应该履行好我的小职责
I am supposed to fulfill my small functions
然后消失
and vanish.
你是怎么看待这些东西的
What do you think of all that?
我不知道
I don't know...
或许我是个女权主义者
Maybe, I'm a feminist?
所以
So...
你觉得这就是我
You think that's me...
不 我也不知道
No, I don't know.
所以你觉得你看了这本书 你就更了解我了
So, you think you know me better because you read that.
不 不
No, no.
那你为什么要念这个给我听
Then why're you reading it to me?
我觉得很有意思
I thought it was interesting.
好吧
Okay, well...
我不需要通过一本书来了解我自己
I don't need a book to know about myself.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我想说 很感谢你试着帮助他 真的
I mean, I appreciate that you trying to help, I do...
但我觉得你有点太过了
I just think you are taking it too far.
这种事情 你知道的...
And this stuff, with you know,
女权运动我也很尊重 但是...
the women's movement I respect, but it's just...
这很复杂 我觉得这对他来说太过了
It's complicated, and I think it's too much for him.
我不明白你指的是什么
I don't know what it is that you're talking about.
好吧 他只是个十五岁的男孩
Okay, he is 15-year-old boy...
- 我知道      - 你给他灌输的是实打实的女权主义思想
- I know...        - You are giving him hard core feminism...
但是他确实热爱这个 而且真的...对他有所帮助
But he really loves it and it's really..it's helping him.
- 帮助他什么      - 帮助他成为一个男人
- Helping him what?        - It's helping him become a man.
这就是你口中的那个男孩
This is the boy you were talking about.
了解女性高潮…
Learning about a female orgasms...
能够帮助他成为一个男人?
is helping him be a man?
你认识有哪个男的在关心这些事吗
Well what man do you know that cares anything about that?
- 这分明是奇迹了      - 他只是个高中生
- It's a miracle!        - He's a high school kid.
好吗
Okay?
这太过了 我跟你这么说
It's too much, I'm telling you.
我认为他似乎完全能够接受
I think he seems really okay with it.
你知道你其实完全不明白自己在对他做什么吗
You know you don't actually know what you're doing with him?
好吗 那么…
Okay, so...
你就...
Just...
正如你们所知的
As you know...
现在人们越来越不尊重政府
There is a growing disrespect for government...
学校 新闻媒体
The schools, the news media...
以及各种机构
And all the institutions.
这不是让人快乐和安心的信号
This is not a message of happiness or reassurance.
这是事实 也是警告
But it is the truth and it is a warning.
这是一场信任危机
It is a crisis of confidence.
吉米・卡特 信任危机演讲 1979年7月15日播出
我们能在日渐增长的
We can see this crisis in the growing doubt...
对自己生活意义的怀疑中
about the meaning of our...
在民族团结和目标的缺失中
own lives and in the loss of unity and purpose...
看到这场危机
for our nation.
电影《失衡生活》 导演 高佛雷・雷吉奥
拍摄于1975-1979 上映于1982
现在我们中的许多人都倾向于崇拜自我放纵
Too many of us now, tend to worship self indulgence...
以及消费
and consumption.
但是我们也发现 占有和消费
But we've discovered that owning things and consuming things.
并不能满足我们对于意义的渴望
does not satisfy...our longing for meaning.
我们一直相信我们是伟大运动的一份子
We always believed that we were part of a great movement.
是人类自身的一份子
Of humanity itself...
以及对自由的追寻
Involved in the search for freedom.
我们正处于历史的转折点
We are at a turning point in our history.
这是一条走向分裂和自我利益的道路
The path that leads to fragmentation and self-interest...
这条路上有着关于自由的错误观念
down that road lies a mistaken idea of freedom.
这条路必定会走向失败
It is a certain route to failure.
谢谢你们 晚安
Thank you and good night.
- 他完全搞砸了      - 可不是吗
- He is so screwed.        - No shit.
他完了
It's over for him.
我觉得他讲得很漂亮
I thought that was beautiful.
好吧
Well...
为什么你不直接道歉
Why didn't you just say I'm sorry?
不玩了
I'm done.
- 我的自尊心…      - 我明白
- My pride...        - I know.
- 是啊      - 你看起来不像是很要强的人
- Yes...        - You don't seem like a prideful person.
- 你看起来很谦虚      - 我今天没把自尊心带来
- You seem humble.       - I left my pride outside today.
杰米 你能把艾比叫醒吗
Jamie, would you please wake up Abbie?
- 嘿 艾比      - 别动我 我在来月经
- Yeah Abbie.!        - Ugh, stop it, I'm menstruating.
艾比 你知道吗 你在来月经 可以
Abbie, you know what? You're menstruating, okay.
但是你非要说出来吗
But do you have to say it, Ok?
我们非得知道你的身体状况吗
Do we really need to know everything that's going on with you?
什么 我在来月经 这有什么大不了的
What? I am menstruating. What is that a big deal?
我们没必要知道 谢谢
We don't need to hear about that, thank you.
如果你想和一个女人发生成人的关系
If you ever wanna have an adult relationship with a woman..
比如你想和她的阴道做爱
Like if you wanna have sex with a woman's vagina,
你得接受阴道会来月经这个事实
You need to be comfortable with the fact that the vagina menstruates
我就会直接说月经
I'm just saying menstruation
没什么说不得的
it's not a big problem.
所以 来吧 开始唱… 月经
So, start singing now... Menstruation.
- 不要      - 就要 月经
- No.        - Yes, menstruation.
- 月经      - 杰米 不用
- Menstruation.        - Jamie, no...
你没必要这样做
You don't have to.
你的语气显得很害怕 别怕说这个词
You saying it like you're scared, don't say like you're scared...
- 平常地说出来      - 月经
- Say it like it's normal.        - Menstruation.
- 月经      - 月经
- Menstruation.        - Menstruation...
还不赖
Not bad.
朱利安 月经 你可以的
Julian, menstruation... You can say it.
- 现在      - 我很遗憾
- Right now...        - I'm Sorry...
月经
Menstruation.
你得...直视我的眼睛
It's just, keep eye contact with me.
你到底在看谁 月经
Who are you looking at? Menstruation.
- 月经      - 好的 对
- Menstruation.        - Yes that's right...
月经 查理 你都不说话
Menstruation, Charlie? You're quiet...
- 月经?      - 月经?
- Menstruation?        - Menstruation?
不 不是疑问句 月经
No, not like a question, menstruation.
月经
Menstruation.
现在大家一起说...
Now everybody say it together...
月经
Menstruation
温柔地 开心地 但随意地说…
like gentle, happy...But casual and...
- 月经      - 恶心死了 艾比
- Menstruation!        - It's gross Abbie.
不 不恶心 这是非常深沉的时刻
No, it's not. It's not gross. It's a very deep time.
富有创造力和情感的塑造
Creatively and it's emotionally trans-formative.
在经期做爱可以让人非常享受
And sex during menstruation can be very pleasurable...
对女人来说 还能缓解部分阵痛
for a woman and can even like, relieve some of the cramps.
杰米 我还想告诉你
Jamie I also wanna say...
永远不要只和阴道做爱
never have sex with just the vagina...
你得和这个女人做爱
You have to have sex with the whole woman.
这个有点偏离了我在说的主题
That's slightly off topic of what I'm talking about.
但是谢谢
Thank you.
我第一次来潮的时候 我正在
The first time that I got my period, I was watching...
和其他人一起看《飞越疯人院》
One that flew over the "Cuckoo's Nest", with some guy...
然后我只说了句我得走了
And...yeah I just told him that I had to leave.
接着我去了超市 买了一盒卫生棉条
So I went to the market and I bought a box of tampons.
我看了盒子上的说明书 然后塞了一根进去
I read the instructions on the box and I put one in.
我从来没和妈妈讲过 她也从来不会问
And I never told my mom about it, but she never asks.
所以无所谓了
So it didn't matter.
我一直没看到《飞越疯人院》的结局
I never saw the end of the Cuckoo's Nest.
杰克・尼克尔森做了额叶切除手术
Jack Nicholson got a lobotomy...
然后那个大个子印度人用枕头把他闷死了
and so the big Indian guy, smothered him with the pillow...
为了让他能够自由
so that he could be, you know, be free.
好吧… 咱们聊点别的
Okay... Let's talk about something else.
十四岁的时候 我第一次做爱
At 14, I had sex for the first time.
朱莉
Julie!
朱莉 拜托 甜心
Julie, please... you, honey...
有一天晚上 我决定要破处
I decided one night that I was just gonna loose my virginity.
- 我无所谓对方是谁      - 朱莉 你冷静一下
- I didn't care who.        - Julie, you gotta to calm down.
别说话 让她讲
Stop it, let her talk.
我在聚会里挑了一个我不认识的人
I picked this guy that I didn't know at a party.
我们做得相当痛苦
And we had fairly painful sex.
就在他停在路边的车里
In his van just parked on the street
用口水来润滑
Just used spit for lubrication.
恶心…
Disgusting...
不过我还是在宵禁前赶回了家
I made it home in time for the curfew though.
他的毯子闻起来像流出的下水道味儿
His carpet smelled like spilled bong water.
好了 今晚就到此为止吧
Well, let's call it a night.
好的
All right.
谢谢你们来 表演结束了姑娘们
Thanks all for coming... show is over girls.
非常感谢你们来
Thank you so much for coming
杰米 我们需要谈谈
Jamie, we need to talk.
发生了好多事 不是吗 我就…
There's a lot of stuff happening... right? And I just...
想知道你现在怎么样了吗
Would like to know what's going on with you.
我是说...
I mean...
我知道对我们来说要处理的事情太多了
I know it's all been a lot for us to deal with.
妈妈
Mom.
现在这些我都能处理
I'm dealing with everything right now.
而你什么都没做
You are dealing with nothing.
真不敢相信你把那些都说给大家听了
Can't believe you told everyone all that.
我想说什么就说什么
I can say what I wanna say.
他们会认为你是个...
They're gonna think you're some...
他们会对你产生错误的看法
They are gonna get the wrong idea about you.
什么
What?
认为我是个荡妇吗
That I'm a slut?
你是这么认为的吗
Is that what you think?
你不可以再只是为了说说话
You can't sleep here anymore...
睡在这里了
And just want to talk...
- 真的吗      - 是的
- really?        - Yes.
杰米
Jamie...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我对不起你 好吗
I am sorry, okay?
我们一起走吧
Let's just get out of here.
沿着海岸走 就像你说过的那样
Let's go up the coast... like you said that you would.
就我们两个
Just the two of us.
妈妈
Mom...
朱莉和我把车开走了
Julie and I took the car...
我们要沿着海岸线去旅行
We're taking a trip up the coast...
离开这里
Just to get away.
你不用担心我们
You don't need to worry about us.
嘿
Hey...
你能帮我们买点果酒吗
Do you think that you could buy us some like wine coolers?
找零归你
You can keep the change,
草莓的或者随便什么莓的都行
strawberry or anything berry really.
- 嗨 怎么了      - 你好
- Hi, what's the matter?        - Hi...
你刚才在十字路口变换了车道
You changed lanes in the intersection back there.
当真 就因为这个?
Seriously, that's all?
请出示你的驾照
I need to see your license registration.
要是我没有驾照呢
What if I don't have my license?
好吧
Okay.
你的名字 住址 出生日期是多少 这些总有吧
What's your name, address, and date of birth, do you have that?
你知道吗 这些是很私人的问题 我们才刚刚见面呢
You know, these are very personal questions and we've just met.
你的名字叫什么 你的住址呢 是吧
What's your name? What's your address, right?
我是说 这样有点太主动了
I mean... It's a little forward...
我爱你
I love you...
你怎么了
What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing.
跟我说说
Tell me.
我觉得我和你靠得太近了
I think that I'm too close to you...
近到无法和你做爱
To have sex with you...
有点复杂
It's confusing...
对不起
Sorry.
我可以帮助你克服
I can help you get over that.
我不想克服
I don't wanna get over that.
不 你想
Yes you do.
你这样就和别的男人一样
You're being like the other guys.
我想要的并不只是 和你做爱
I don't want to just, have sex with you,
我想要的是你
I want you...
但那只是你以为的我
But it's your version of me.
并不是真的我
It's not me.
你只是想要做爱的话 倒还好得多
It'd be a lot better if you just wanted sex
你现在就和别的男人一模一样
You're exactly like the other guys...
你只是看起来像现代主义者
You just seem like you are a modern.
杰米?
Jamie?
杰米
Jamie.
杰米!
Jamie!
这些人一点幽默感都没有
These people have no sense of humor.
养一个孩子似乎是
Having a kid seems like...
- 最难的事      - 是啊
- The hardest thing.        - Yeah...
你有多爱这个孩子
How much you love the kid...
你就能把事情搞得多砸
you're just pretty much screwed.
- 给你做的      - 嗨
- It's for you.        - Hi.
嘿
Hey.
朱莉刚才打电话给我说他们在圣路易斯・奥比斯波市
Julie just called me, they are in San Luis Obispo,
她不知道他去哪了
she doesn't know where he is.
她找不到他
She can't find him.
我...
I...
- 你能送我吗      - 可以
- Would you drive me?        - Yes, I will.
- 去那吗      - 这就走
- Out there?        - Yeah let's go..
- 你一起吗      - 一起
- Will you come?        - Yes.
对不起
I'm sorry...
他回来了
He came back.
就在那边
He's right there.
好的 好的
Okay... Okay.
没事了
It's okay.
嗯
Well...
朱莉真是个很复杂的女人
Julie is... pretty complicated woman.
要承受的太多了
It's a lot to take on.
某种程度上 我还挺印象深刻
I'm impressed in a way.
管她呢
Whatever.
你不去找朱莉来吗 让她来找我说说话
Aren't you going to get Julie? To come talk with me?
- 杰米      - 怎么了
- Jamie?        - What?
我认为她们能帮你
I thought they'd help.
看起来就像是你拿我没办法了
Well..It just seemed like you couldn't deal with me anymore.
听着
Look.
我想… 我...
I wanted... I...
我...
Look, I...
我不想你走向和我一样的结局
I don't want you to end up in the same place as me.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
我希望你能比我开心
Well, I wanted you to be happier.
而我不觉得这是我自己一个人可以办到
And I just didn't think I could do it by myself. I...
你可以办到
You're right.
我认为即便就我们俩 我们也可以很好
I thought we were fine though just me and you.
真的吗
Yeah?
真的
Yeah.
好的 来
Okay. Come...
来和妈妈跳舞
Come and dance with your mom.
- 再见      - 再见
- Bye.        - Bye.
再见
Bye.
再见 再见 再见
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye.
可能我们还不急着回去
So maybe we don't go back yet?
好啊
Okay.
- 你和爸爸相爱过吗      - 当然
- Were you and Dad ever in love?        - Sure.
或者说
Or um...
可能我只是
Maybe I was just...
我只是认为应该是相爱的 或者...
I thought that was supposed to be in love. Or..
我害怕自己从来没爱过
I was scared I'd never be in love.
所以我...
So I...
我那时选择了最好的解决办法
I just pick the best solution at the time.
- 我想漂染我的头发      - 孩子
- I want to bleach my hair.        - Kid...
- 真的吗     - 是的
- Really?        - Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
你孤单吗
Are you lonely?
亨弗莱・鲍嘉 电影《卡萨布兰卡》的男主角
嗯... 我下辈子可能会嫁给鲍嘉
Well... I might marry Bogart in my next life...
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
我是这么想的
I'm thinking about it.
他都死了
He is dead.
好吧
Well...
我们在说下辈子 不是吗 所以...
This is my next life, right? So...
他可能活着 可能在那 我们可能会相遇
He may be there... may be around, and we might meet and..
可能在我们之间会发生点什么
something might happen between us.
好吧
Okay..
你就不能在现实世界拥有这些吗
You can't have it in the real world?
现在可不是理性的时候 宝贝
Hey, this is no time to be rational, sweetie.
- 你就不能顺着我说的吗      - 可以 继续吧
- Can you just go with this?        - Yeah, keep going.
好
Okay.
然后他了解我的想法
So he knows what I'm thinking
他能让我开怀大笑
And he makes me laugh...
而且 他能真正看到我
And... he really sees me.
而且 你知道他会说到做到的
And... You know that he's gonna do what he says he's gonna do.
- 就这么简单      - 听起来很棒
- So that's easy...        - It sounds nice.
是啊
Yeah.
Yeah...
我认为从此我和她开始了一段全新的关系
I thought that was just the beginning of a new relationship with her.
就在她真正向我倾诉的时刻开始
where she'd really tell me stuff.
但是也许再也不会有像这样的时候了
But maybe it was never really like that again.
也许就这样了
Maybe that was it.
1999年3月 我会开始感到劳累和糊涂
In March of 1999, I'll start to feel tired and confused.
当我终于去看医生的时候
When I finally go to the doctor,
他会告诉我 我肺部的癌细胞
he will say that the cancer in my lungs...
已经扩散到了我的胸部和大脑
had already traveled to my breast and brain.
我会试着教杰米如何处理我的股票
I'll try to teach Jamie what to do with my stocks.
但我的笔迹会让人几乎看不明白
but my instructions will be impossible to understand.
艾比会带我去计生所
Abbie will take me to Planned Parenthood...
我会继续吃药
And I will go on the pill.
我会去纽约大学念书 和杰米还有多萝西娅失去联络
I will go to NYU and lose touch with Jamie and Dorothea.
我会不再和妈妈讲话
and I will stop talking to my mom.
我会和尼古拉斯相爱
I will fall in love with Nicholas.
我们会搬去巴黎
We will move to Paris.
并且选择不要小孩
and choose not to have children.
我会留在圣巴巴拉
I'll stay in Santa Barbara.
两年之后我会嫁给戴夫
In just two years I will marry Dave.
我结婚后的一个月 卡洛塔会死去
A month after I get married Carlotta will die.
一个星期后 马克思也会死去
A week later... Max will die too.
我会从车库里工作
I will work out of my garage.
然后在当地艺廊里展出
and show in local galleries.
我会不顾医生的建议去怀孕
Against my doctor's advice, I will get pregnant..
到我34岁的时候 我会有两个儿子
by the time I'm 34 I'll have two boys...
我会和多萝西娅一起再生活一年
I'll live with Dorothea for another year.
然后我会开一家陶器店
And then I'll open a pottery store.
在亚利桑那州塞多纳市
In Sedona, Arizona.
我会和一个叫劳丽的原创歌手结婚
I will marry Laurie a singer-songwriter...
我们会在一年后离婚 接着我会遇见桑迪
We'll get divorced a year...Then I'll meet Sandy.
并且继续做我的陶器
And continue to do my pottery.
我妈妈会在1983年遇见吉姆
My mom will meet Jim in 1983...
他们会一直是夫妻 直到她去世
they'll stay a couple until she dies.
每年她生日的时候
On her birthday each year,
他都会送她一次双翼飞机的飞行
he will buy her a trip on a biplane.
在她去世好多年后
Years after she's gone...
我会终于结婚并且有一个儿子
I'll finally get married and have a son.
我会尝试向他说明 他的奶奶是个什么样的人
I'll try to explain to him what his grandmother was like.
但我永远无法说清
but it will be impossible.
Rudy Vallée- As Time Goes By?
更多咨询请关注官方公众号：cinematik
奇遇电影字幕组
QY-182
翻译   阿囤小兄弟
翻译   FantaJoe
翻译   StillWhale
翻译   butterfliesaway
校对   一个Delpy
特效&压制   33-eR
蓝光调轴   Bryan-T
Buzzcocks- Why Can’t I Touch It?